{
  "age": 71,
  "aliases": [
    "/us-senate/blaine-taylor/"
  ],
  "background": "US Army Soldier under enemy Viet Cong fire, South Vietnam, 1966-67, Combat Infantryman's Badge; campaign & Congressional press secretary, Capitol Hill, DC, with four winning campaigns for others, 1974-92; black newspaper reporter, freelance magazine writer, published author of 22 books worldwide, 1993-2018; appointee to city and county boards by mayor and county executive, confirmed by both city & county councils",
  "directory": "content/primary/us-senate",
  "dob": "12/8/1946",
  "education": "BA History Major Towson State College 1972. Minor: Political Science",
  "filename": "blaine-taylor.md",
  "full-name": "Blaine Taylor",
  "jurisdiction": "Baltimore County",
  "last-name": "Taylor",
  "party": "Republican",
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "How do you assess the Trump administration so far?",
      "answer": "Many successes: Mexican border security. North Korea has backed down 100%, no new war yet anywhere abroad, economy booming, un-employment at 4%, tax cuts enacted, tariff sanctions both needed and imposed on China, and no 2nd domestic civil war here---yet.",
      "shortname": "Trump record"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you support or oppose the federal tax cuts passed in 2017? What effect do you believe they will have on the economy?",
      "answer": "Thus far, yes, but I'd look at them afresh upon entering office in January 2019; for now, I am following the lead of Democratic MD State Comptroller Peter Franchot, who has asserted: \"A large group of Marylanders benefit directly...71%...are going to have $ 3.5 BILLION in new, disposable income...(a) stimulus to the economy.\" As for the longer term effects, we'll have to see. Make Trump release HIS tax returns a MUST.",
      "shortname": "2017 Tax Cuts"
    },
    {
      "question": "Is the level of national debt a concern? What, if anything, should be done to reduce it or constrain its increase?",
      "answer": "Yes, stop spending beyond balanced budgets period. Reduce all government bureaucracies, and create NO MORE new ones! Make the 1% at the top pay its fair share, with no exceptions. Imprison deadbeat offenders.",
      "shortname": "National debt"
    },
    {
      "question": "Is the level of economic inequality in the United States a problem, and if so, what should the federal government do to address it?",
      "answer": "Yes. Publish all salaries everywhere of everyone, no exceptions. Enforce the already passed 1955 Federal legislation re: equal pay for equal work across the board, that has yet to be enforced.",
      "shortname": "Income inequality"
    },
    {
      "question": "Should federal gun laws be changed, and if so, how?",
      "answer": "Yes, outlaw all assault rifles, bump stocks, and high capacity magazines. I personally fired most of what the Army had during 1965-67, and co-founded the TSC Pistol, Rifle & Shotgun Club in 1971-72. Execute ALL killers without life sentences, with no parole or exceptions, period. Pass universal background checks. Raise the purchasing age from 18 to 21.",
      "shortname": "Gun laws"
    },
    {
      "question": "What should Congress do with respect to the Affordable Care Act? Should it be strengthened, and if so, how? Should it be scrapped? If so, what if anything should replace it?",
      "answer": "As with Social Security after 1935, the ACA should be reformed, in concert with the newer Trump Care, and not repealed. Upon taking office, I'll craft together the best aspects of both. In general, I favor a single-payer, cradle-to-grave system that covers all citizens.",
      "shortname": "ACA"
    },
    {
      "question": "What role should the federal government play in helping cities like Baltimore?",
      "answer": "Audit how all Federally granted monies since 1965 were actually spent---so that we don't make the same mistakes again--then proceed anew. Revoke the Baltimore City Charter, pension off the current mayor, abolish the Office of the Mayor, place the City under the State Governor, and have that person appoint a City Manager who reports to the Governor only. Consider aboilishing the already top-heavy City Council also. Since the departure of the late William Donald Schaefer, the city has gone downhill uninterrupted.",
      "shortname": "Urban policy"
    },
    {
      "question": "What can Congress do to address the opioid epidemic?",
      "answer": "Execute suppliers and dealers.",
      "shortname": "Opioids"
    },
    {
      "question": "What changes if any should Congress make to our immigration and deportation laws and policies?",
      "answer": "Secure the borders, deport all illegal aliens, enforce all current US laws, outlaw all illegal \"sanctuary\" sites, and fire/jail their practitioners---and elected officials--who counsel breaking our laws. Fire the current TU President who advocates a sanctuary campus. Build The Wall, and permananetly station Regular US Army divisions on the Mexican border now. Send home the National Guard units to their jobs and families",
      "shortname": "Immigration"
    },
    {
      "question": "Should the United States continue with the free trade policies it pursued for the last several decades, or should it enact restrictions in an attempt to help domestic industries?",
      "answer": "No. Repeal NAFTA ASAP. Support the President's tariff sanctions against bandit China.",
      "shortname": "Free trade"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you support the Iran nuclear deal?",
      "answer": "No. Repeal it ASAP. Let the Israelies destroy Iranian nuclear plants as they have done others in the past. I support Israel on this.",
      "shortname": "Iran"
    },
    {
      "question": "How should the United States address the rise of North Koreaâ€™s nuclear program?",
      "answer": "End it, and destroy all its nuclear weapons and ICBM rocketry.",
      "shortname": "North Korea"
    }
  ],
  "race": "us-senate",
  "residence": "Towson",
  "social-fb": "blainetaylor",
  "survey-response": false,
  "title": "Blaine Taylor"
}
